# John Olatubosun - Software Engineer

toluolatubosun@gmail.com; +234 908 451 2241; Lagos, Nigeria

LINKS	https://www.linkedin.com/in/john-olatubosun https://toluolatubosun.com	https://github.com/toluolatubosun https://medium.com/@toluolatubosun			
PROFILE	John Olatubosun is a Software Engineer with 2 years of professional work experience. His major strengths are in backend development and cloud engineering; while also having substantial experience in frontend, mobile development, data science, machine learning and AI				

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Oct 2023 - Present Software Engineer I - Left Lane Technologies

## June 2022 - Sep 2023 Software Engineer (Part-time) - Left Lane Technologies

- Developed robust REST and GraphQL APIs using Node.js, enhancing application performance and scalability
- Integrated Stripe and Paystack payment gateways into multiple applications, streamlining payment processes and improving user experience.
- Implemented MongoDB and Redis databases for efficient data storage and retrieval, ensuring high availability and performance.
- Integrated a variety of third-party APIs and services (Klaviyo, TikTok API, Facebook API, Instagram API, YouTube API, Twitter API, Sentry, Adobe Express AI) to expand application functionality.
- Utilized AWS services (AWS SES, S3, ACM, Elastic Beanstalk, CodePipeline, CodeBuild, ElastiCache, Amplify, API Gateway, Route 53) to build, deploy, and manage scalable applications.
- Implemented microservice communication with RabbitMQ for efficient task processing.
- Led an engineering team following Agile methodology, ensuring timely delivery of high-quality software products.
- Major Projects: Plugtent, Custom Mailers Depot

#### Nov 2023 - Present Backend Developer - Credit Cliq

- Utilized various AWS services (AWS SES, S3, Cognito) for building and managing scalable applications.
- Integrated APIs with multiple credit bureaus to retrieve credit history and ensure compliance with regulations.
- Implemented Stripe payment services to manage invoices and subscriptions seamlessly.
- Developed robust REST APIs in Node.js for mobile apps, web apps, and admin panels, ensuring efficient data communication.
- Built and maintained admin panels using Next.js 14, enhancing user and administrative functionality.
- Worked with Redis and MongoDB for efficient data storage and utilized MongoDB Queues for background job processing.
- Implemented microservice communication with Apache Kafka for efficient task processing.
- Implemented and deployed microservice applications to AWS lambda for efficient handle of complex process.
- Project: Credit Cliq

## **SKILLS**

JavaScript	/TypeScrip	t Pytho	n SQL	MongoDB	Redis	RabbitMQ	Apache Kafka
Docker	Linux	AWS	Node.JS	React / Next.JS	GraphQ	L Nest.JS	Django
VS Code	Machine l	earning/Al	Data Structu	res and Algorithms	s Micros	ervice Git/	GitHub

## **EDUCATION & CERTIFICATION**

## BACHELORS OF SCIENCE, COMPUTER SCIENCE

MOUNTAIN TOP UNIVERSITY | 2019 - 2023

- Graduated with First Class Honors 4.89/5.00 CGPA
- Ranked 3rd overall in academic achievement among the graduating class.
- Best Graduating Student in the Department of Computer Science and Mathematics
- Vice President of the Computer Science Association

## **NOTEABLE PERSONAL PROJECTS**

June 2022 - Aug 2023 MySvote

- Developed a highly customizable and secure online voting platform, Mysvote, using Node.js, React, TailwindCSS, and MongoDB.
- Implemented robust database transactions to ensure data integrity and security.
- Attracted over 2,000 users and successfully hosted three institutional awards ceremonies.
- Mysvote

Jan 2023 - Aug 2023 Gild

- Developed Gild, a platform for cross-border money transfers using centralized tokens, built with Node.js, GraphQL, Next.js, and MongoDB.
- Integrated Stripe payment service for secure and efficient transactions.
- Showcased the platform during an academic conference, demonstrating its innovative features and capabilities.
- Gild